# SHRATHINTH VENKATESH

 $(262) \cdot 421 \cdot 5281 \diamond \text{venkate3@uwm.edu}$ 1714, E. Beverly Rd, #7 ♦ Shorewood, WI 53211 shrathinth.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Economist/Applied micro-econometrician with a track record of consistently and creatively solving a diverse set of problems. Experienced with analysing survey data and medical claims data from public and private insurance providers. Implemented a wide variety of empirical strategies to examine changes in labour market outcomes, health outcomes and their effects. Drawn robust conclusions from limited data and indirect treatment observation.

# **EDUCATION**

## University of Wisconsin - Milwaukee

(Expected) 2021

PhD in Economics

Focus: Labor Economics, Economics of Education, Health Economics

## PES Institute of Technology, India

2013

BE in Mechanical Engineering

Focus: Material Science

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Graduate Research Assistant

August 2017 - December 2019

College of Nursing, Department of Economics

University of Wisconsin - Milwaukee

- · Assessed the impact of the PERISCOPE perinatal health intervention using claims data from Medicaid and private insurance providers in Wisconsin.
- · Used propensity score matching and difference-in-differences regressions to find a 20% increase in prescription use and a \$310 reduction in emergency costs.
- · Used machine learning techniques including random forest, decision tree and K-nearest neighbours in R for variable selection and testing.
- · Reported the results of our study in non-technical language.
- · Communicated and worked with health professionals to create appropriate empirical models.

#### Lecturer

September 2020 - May 2021

Department of Economics

University of Wisconsin - Whitewater

- · Teaching applied business statistics and principles of microeconomics.
- · Creating content and teaching students in a Hy-Flex format.

### Graduate Teaching Assistant

August 2014 - May 2020

University of Wisconsin - Milwaukee Department of Economics

- · Taught a diverse set of students with a wide range of technical backgrounds.
- · Clearly communicated technical statistics and econometrics.
- · Taught data analysis using R and STATA to undergraduate and graduate students with little prior knowledge.
- · Had full control of 4 different courses across 8 semesters.

# TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Skills		Applied econometrics, Machine learning, Data Analysis
Tools	Proficient	STATA, R, Matlab, IAT <sub>E</sub> X
	Familiar	Python, SQL, SAS, SPSS, E-Views, JAVA, C++

## RESEARCH

"The Emerging College Hours Premium for Men" (revision a	sked for by Educati	ion Econo	mics)
"The Returns to Drinking: Workers or Jobs?" with SJ Adams, JS Hey	wood & D Ullman	Working	Paper
"Are the Returns to Education Still Rising?"		Working	Paper
"Changes in the Returns to Education: Evidence from Three Cohorts of	of the NLSY"	Working	Paper
"Estimating the Effects of the Periscope Project" with SJ Adams & JJ	Doering	In Pr	rogress
"Changes in education's effect on job sorting"		In Pr	rogress

# PRESENTATIONS AND HONORS

Midwest Economic Association Annual Meeting, St.Louis, MO	2019
Wisconsin Economics Association Annual Meeting, Stevens Point, WI	2019
University of Wisconsin - Milwaukee Economics Labor Lunch	2019
University of Wisconsin - Milwaukee Applied Microeconomics group	2019
Richard Perlman Prize for Outstanding Paper in Labor Economics	2018
University of Wisconsin - Milwaukee Chancellors Graduate student award	2014 & 2015

# PROFESSIONAL SERVICE

Midwest Economic Association Annual Meeting, St. Louis, MO	Discussant	2019
Graduate Student Applied Microeconomics Group, UWM	${\it Co-organizer}$	2019

## PROFESSIONAL ASSOCIATIONS

American Economic Association Midwest Economic Association

### REFERENCES

Provided upon request.